Alessandro Simoni

PhD Student @ Department of Engineering "Enzo Ferrari"

Modena, Italy

C +39 334 8040595 | ■ alle.simoni.as@gmail.com | 😭 alexj94.github.io | 🛅 LinkedIn | 🞓 Google Scholar

Summary _

I'm a PhD student under the tutorship of Prof. Roberto Vezzani at the International Doctorate School in ICT (Unimore, Italy) with the following research topic: "Computer Vision and Artificial Intelligence for Collaborative Robotic Environments".

My main interests are in Human-centric AI and Robotics exploiting deep learning and computer vision techniques applied to the 3D world. My research skills are related to 3D pose estimation of articulated objects and 3D object reconstruction through neural rendering techniques. I am also collaborating on a project related to the 3D reconstruction of vehicles through NeRF approaches.

Knowledge and computer skills _____

Programming languages Python (proficiency), C++, JavaScript **Libraries and Tools** PyTorch, NumPy, OpenCV, PyCharm

Domains Deep Learning, 2D/3D Computer Vision, 3D Human/Robot Pose Estimation, 3D Reconstruction

Spoken languages Italian mothertongue, English C1 (certifed ESOL Cambridge)

Working experiences _____

Research grant

AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

July 2023 - ongoing

Supervisor: Prof. Roberto Vezzani

Project: "Al platform with digital twins of interacting robots and people"

AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

Research grant June 2022 - June 2023

Supervisor: Prof. Roberto Vezzani

Project: "Study of recent combinations of CNN and Vision Transformer architectures"

AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

Research grant May 2020 - May 2022

Supervisor: Prof. Roberto Vezzani

Project: "PREVUE - Prediction of Activities and Events by Vision in an Urban Environment"

AlmageLab - University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

Student internship for master's degree thesis

July 2019 - Feb. 2020

Supervisor: Prof. Rita Cucchiara

"Future urban scene generation: a deep learning approach for a 3D temporal vehicle reconstruction starting from monocular images"

Education _____

University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

PhD student - Curriculum "Computer engineering and science"

Nov. 2020 - ongoing

Supervisor: Prof. Roberto Vezzani

University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

University of Modena and Reggio Emilia

Modena, Italy

Master's degree in computer engineering

Sep. 2017 - Feb. 2020

• GPA: 27.806/30. Final grade: 108/110

Modena, Italy

Bachelor's degree in computer engineering

Sep. 2013 - Feb. 2017

• GPA: 23.607/30. Final grade: 91/110

Certifications _

First Certificate in English (FCE) Grade A (Score 180), University of Cambridge ESOL Examinations	Dec. 2020
4^{th} Advanced Course on Data Science and Machine Learning (ACDL 2021) Participation certificate with final exam	July 2021
16^{th} International Computer Vision Summer School (ICVSS 2022) Participation certificate with final exam	July 2022
Selected publications	
Complete list on Google Scholar.	
<u>Journals</u>	
Pattern Recognition Letters (PRL) A.D'Eusanio, A. Simoni, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani, R.Cucchiara "Depth-based 3D human pose refinement: Evaluating the refinet framework"	Mar. 2023
IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L) A. Simoni, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani "Semi-Perspective Decoupled Heatmaps for 3D Robot Pose Estimation from Depth Maps" The paper was presented during IROS 2022 conference held in Kyoto, Japan.	Oct. 2022
Informatics A. D'Eusanio, A. Simoni, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani, R. Cucchiara "Multimodal hand gesture classification for the human-car interaction"	Aug. 2020
Conferences	
23^{rd} International Conference on Image Analysis and Processing D. Di Nucci, A. Simoni, M. Tomei, L. Ciuffreda, R. Vezzani, R. Cucchiara "CarPatch: A Synthetic Benchmark for Radiance Field Evaluation on Vehicle Components"	Udine, Italy 11-15 Sept. 2023

	,			
Oth Intow	national Conferen	an an 2D Vision		
9°°° inter	national Conferen	ce on 3D vision		

Virtual, Online 1-3 Dec. 2021

A. Simoni, S. Pini, R. Vezzani, R. Cucchiara "Multi-category mesh reconstruction from image collections"

Virtual, Online 8-10 Feb. 2021

A. Simoni, A. D'Eusanio, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani "Improving car model classification through vehicle keypoint localization"

Virtual, Online

 25^{th} International Conference on Pattern Recognition A. Simoni, L. Bergamini, A. Palazzi, S. Calderara, R. Cucchiara "Future urban scene generation through vehicle synthesis"

10-15 Jan. 2021

 $8^{th}\,$ International Conference on 3D Vision

Virtual, Online

A. D'Eusanio, A. Simoni, S. Pini, G. Borghi, R. Vezzani, R. Cucchiara "A transformer-based network for dynamic hand gesture recognition"

25-28 Nov. 2020

2

Additional information _____

Citizenship Italian, German

16th VISIGRAPP

Travelling Passport, B license, own car

According to law 679/2016 of the Regulation of the European Parliament of 27th April 2016, I hereby express my consent to process and use my data provided in this document and application for recruiting purposes.